# Kenan Bölükbaşı

Керан Андреев Давидов | Keran Andreev Davidov

# Game Developer & Designer, CG Generalist, Architect

*	İSTANBUL - TURKEY
C	+ 90 (542) 5362620
8	KENANBOLUKBASI
	KENANB@6x13.COM
	KENANBOLUKBASI@GMAIL.COM
•	☑ KENANB.COM ☑ 6X13.COM # BFCT
	Mobile: 🛊 🖣 📕 🚨 Desktop: 🖵 🥝
	♥ KENANBOLUKBASI 🔊 BLOG.6x13.COM
>	C KENANB C 6x13

# SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Theoretical and applied knowledge in programming, design and media. Broad experience in project management. Experience in 3D (mesh, solid & CAD), 2D (raster, vector), and parametric graphics as well as asset pipelines and tools development. Blender 3D specialist (Blender Foundation Certified Trainer).

# PERSONAL DETAILS

CITIZENSHIP Turkish, Bulgarian

B Class DRIVER'S LICENCE

28th January 1987, Bulgaria DATE & PLACE OF BIRTH

### **EDUCATION**

2005 - 2017	<b>Architecture (B.Arch.)</b> Istanbul Technical University, ITU School of Architecture, İstanbul
2001 - 2005	<b>High School (Science and Math)</b> Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School, Bursa

# CONFERENCES & WORKSHOPS

# TALKS GIVEN

2016	Toxicity in Gaming: Negative Effects of Prioritizing Player Motivation in World Design ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul
2014	<b>Prototyping &amp; Optimizing Game Asset Workflow</b> Blender Conference, Amsterdam
2014	<b>Automated Sprite Rendering System in Blender</b> Libre Graphics Meeting, Leipzig
2014	<b>Blender Python Programming Workshop</b> BlendFX Studios, Leipzig
2011	<b>AudioSpaces LiveCoding Workshop</b> ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul

# P

Participation			
	2015	Game Developers Conference EU 2015 (Cologne) UBM Tech	
	2014	<b>Blender Conference (Amsterdam)</b> Blender Foundation	
	2014	Libre Graphics Meeting (Leipzig)  LGM Crew	
	2014	<b>Blender Python Workshop (Leipzig)</b> Kenan Bölükbaşı	
	2011	IAF Compositing Workshop (İstanbul) Özgür Gülbir	

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## 6x13 Games, İstanbul

JAN 2015 - [ CONT'D ]

# Founder, Project Leader & Developer

Project leader. Game design and development. Graphic design and game asset creation. Prototyping, pipeline optimization.

- Design, development and artwork of WRECKJUMPER[WIP], forced-perspective sci-fi TBS with dynamic puzzle elements.
- Game design, development, project management, graphics and user interface design of TWINIWT, the globally featured free to play symmetrical movement puzzle.
- Project management & development of 1FPS GAME SERIES. 4 free to play handheld console games. The titles are:
  - 1FPS: INVADERS
  - 1FPS: VACUUM
  - 1FPS: FASTFOOD
  - 1FPS: GRAFFITI[WIP]
- Cocos2d-x based in-house cross-platform game framework.
- Data structure design and development of the visualization module for an architectural research project, FAÇADE, at ITU. It aims to develop facades using evolutionary algorithms.
- Development of Fossicker, open source asset prospector.
- Invited industry participant at some Architectural Design Computing Master's Program classes at ITU.

### EKSERIYA STUDIOS, İSTANBUL Aug 2013 - Jan 2015 Graphics Department Lead & TD

Decision making on graphics technology and workflow. Workflow optimization software development. Game asset creation, shading and lighting. Pipeline integration and prototyping.

- Asset pipeline automation system (import, lighting, rendering, compositing & atlas) for mobile RTS, SILICON WARS.
- Environment art and map editor for RIOT DEFENSE game.
- Pseudo 3D graphics R&D for FOOTBALL WIZARD game as-

### FREELANCE, İSTANBUL

Jun 2011 - Feb 2014

### Visualization Artist

Archviz for various firms. Modeling & rendering of office furniture catalog of Bürosit as well as indoor visualizations.

### EFOR EVENTS & SIMMETRICO, BAKU AUG 2011 - SEP 2011 Assistant Site Manager

Construction site management of a large steel structure for the wedding event of Azerbaijani President İlham Aliyev's daughter, in a multinational (Italian, Turkish & Azerbaijani) environment.

### SosyalMedya.CO, İstanbul FEB 2011 - MAR 2012 Author

Tech industry reports. Column in monthly e-journal. Interview with former Turkey & MEA Marketing Manager of Google.

# EFOR EVENTS, İSTANBUL **Event Supervisor**

JUL 2010 - APR 2013

Workflow & stage manager. Major events: Windows 8 Turkey Launch, Kenan Doğulu concert, VIP trip to Czech Republic. Clients: Microsoft, TeliaSonera, Huawei, Volvo, Doğuş, Soyak.

### Aşçıoğlu İnşaat, İstanbul SEP 2009 - Nov 2009 Assistant Site Manager, Internship

Application supervision at Acıbadem Hospital building of Selenium Twins (BJK Süleyman Seba Complex) construction site.

### ALPO ENGINEERING, İSTANBUL MAR 2007 - MAY 2007 3D Artist

Technical drawings, archviz, urban planning modeling.

### PROJECTS & RECOGNITION

### PROGRAMMING PROJECTS

#### Twiniwt Mobile Game, 6x13 Games 2017

An innovative symmetrical movement puzzle. Globally featured in the AppStore Puzzle and Board categories as well as the AppStore Turkey homepage. It works on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Uses modified Cocos2d-x game engine, C and C++.

#### 2016 1FPS Retro Game Series, 6x13 Games

4 games that work on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Uses customized Cocos2d-x and C++.

#### 2015 Fossicker, The Asset Prospector, 6x13 Games

An asset generator that regexp over asset name to create relevant dummies. Powerful plugin system relies on CLOS and Context Oriented Programming.

#### 2014 Riot Game Map Editor, Ekseriya

Map editor, importer/exporter that lets users both define and tile assets on a grid, export & raytrace the scene. Uses Blender Game Engine and Python.

#### 2013 Sprite Automation System, Ekseriya

A system for automated game asset creation workflow. Uses Python, Blender3D (BPY) and Bash.

### Hy Programming Language Blender Integration 2013 Blender Python Module that adds HyLang support

### 2012

Common Lisp parser/reader and writer for IESNA LM-63 Photometry Standard files.

and lets users interactively script Blender using Hy.

#### 2011 **TwitGraph**

CL bubble diagram generator. Searchs & visualizes relationships among a #hashtag and its neighbours.

### **DESIGN PROJECTS**

- 2016 ITU Architecture Program Senior Design Project Habitation for Syrian refugees, with a focus on integration and employment, in Süleymaniye, İstanbul.
- StumpWM Window Manager & HyLang Logos 2014 Winner of StumpWM Official Logo Design Contest. Official logo design of Hy Programming Language.
- 2010 Cankaya Ulvi Cemal Erkin Concert Hall & Cultural Center Architectural Design Competition Participation (with Gülsev Özbelen & Gizem Kaya)
- Nooka International Watch Design Competition 2010 Participation with Nooka Ploog-In Design
- 2009 **Akçansa Concrete Ideas Competition** Finalist (with Büşra Atabek)

## COMMUNICATION SKILLS

### **ENGLISH**

• Listening: C2 (Mastery)\* Reading: C2 (Mastery)\*

• Spoken Interaction: C2 (Mastery)\* Spoken Production: C1 (Advanced)\*

• Writing: C2 (Mastery)\*

- Prep Class Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School Technical English – ITU Academic Essay Writing – ITU Research Paper Writing - ITU
- Work experience in Baku in a multinational environment for a month. Ensuring communication among Italian, Turkish, Azerbaijani and other parties.

Work experience in Prague for two weeks.

Guidance to several VIP clients including top government officials and corporate executives.

Constant interaction with foreign English speakers via technical/social platforms and mail.

### AZERBAIJANI

- Listening: B2 (Upper intermediate)\* Reading: B1 (Intermediate)\*
- A2 (Elementary)\*
- A1 (Beginner)\*
- · Work experience for a month in Baku. Several organizations with Azerbaijani clients.

### TURKISH

- Native Speaker
- (\*) Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

### SOFTWARE SKILLS

### GRAPHICS SOFTWARE

Blender 3D Inkscape 9999 ImageMagick, FFMpeg 00000 GIMP, Photoshop 3D Studio Max, Maya 999 00000 **BI & Cycles Renderers** Luxrender, Yafaray 00000 AutoCAD, DraftSight

### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

9999 C / C++

00000 Common Lisp, Scheme Python, Factor 00000

Luminance HDR

UNIX / Shell 

> Lua, HTML5

### DEVELOPMENT TOOLS & LIBRARIES

Emacs 0000 Visual Studio GCC, Clang, MSBuild GDB, LLDB, Valgrind Make, CMake, Gradle 00000 Git Version Control System Cocos2d-x Game Engine (C++) Xcode, Android Studio 

### OPERATING SYSTEMS

GNU/Linux (Arch, Debian) 00000 Windows XP/7/8/10 00000 macOS

### DOCUMENTATION UTILITIES

99999 T<sub>E</sub>X / L<sup>A</sup>T<sub>E</sub>X Systems Org-Mode, Markdown Doxygen, Pandoc 00000 MS Office, Libre Office, Scribus 

### Additional Information

Walking, Computer Science, Technology HOBBIES

Blogging, Literature, Charcoal Drawing

Free / Libre & Open Source Software, COMMUNITIES Blender Network, Lisp Game Development,

Factor Language Development